Kamran Amini

+31 (0) 611060215

Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com Github: github.com/kamcpp

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kamcpp December 14, 2018 Page 1

IN SUMMARY

As a highly motivated and senior software architect, while having spent more than 10 years in developing and architecting enterprise and distributed software for international companies, my skills cover a wide variety of development tools and platforms. The enterprise projects which I've been involved include a wide range of technologies, patterns, and concepts based on embedded C, C++, Java, Scala, Python, relational and NoSQL databases, etc. As a senior software engineer, I have strong hands on writing codes with various programming languages including C, C++, Java, Scala, Python, and bash scripting while having best practices and enterprise patterns in mind. As a distributed system engineer, I've always encountered with strict and tough functional and non-functional requirements in which security, performance, data consistency, distribution of resources, fault tolerance, high availability, authentication, and authorization have been among them. Recently, I've been working as an expert software engineer at TomTom as a part of Search team in order to make it better and give the customers a better search experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Langs: C++11- C11 Java Python Scala
- Paradigms: Procedural OOP Functional Multithreading Multiprocessing MQM Event Driven Dev. (libuv, Java NIO)
- Data Stores: PostgreSQL MySQL MongoDB Redis Cassandra
- Computer Science: Balanced Trees Graphs Index Trees Sort & Search Algs Compression Algs
- Distributed Systems: DFS Dist. Processing Dist. Caching Dist. Key-Value Stores FT and HA strategies DMQ (Kafka)
- Serialization & RPC: protobuf gRPC Thrift Json over REST Java RMI XMLRPC
- Cryptography: OpenSSL Symmetric Algs (DES, 3DES, AES) Asymmetric Algs (RSA, DH) SSL PKI (CA, Digital Signature, PKCS certs, HSMs and Tokens) Hash Algs MACs Error Detection & Correction Algs
- Kernel Dev.: Linux Modules Linux SysCalls FreeBSD Modules
- Machine Learning: CUDA Tensorflow DSP OpenCV Supervised & unsupervised learning Reinforced Learning Deep Learning
- Computer Networks: L3 protocols (ICMP, IP) L4 protocols (UDP, TCP) Socket Programming L3 programming Wireshark analysis
- \bullet $\mathbf{SCMs:}$ Git Perforce Mercurial Subversion
- Build Systems: CMake Ninja Gradle Maven sbt
- IDEs: Vim as IDE IntelliJ IDEA
- DevOps Related: Bash Scripting Perl KVM Docker Jenkins Zabbix
- Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, Red Hat) UNIX like OSs (Mac OS, FreeBSD, QNX) Windows
- CI: Jenkins QuickBuild
- Scrum: Jira Fisheye Confluence Bitbucket Stash

RECENT CAREER

• TomTom

Netherlands, Amsterdam

September 2017 - December 2018 (1 year, 4 months)

Expert Software Engineer

• I was part of the Search team inside the Navigation PU. We were working on different search engines utilizing different kinds of maps, exposing search and POI information services as some RESTful endpoints (NavKit Worker) hosted on AWS/Azure cloud platforms, and as an embedded native engine (NavKit) for QNX, Andorid and iOS devices.

• Jeppesen Systems (Boeing)

Sweden, Gothenburg

February 2017 - August 2017 (6 months)

Expert Software Engineer

Kamran Amini

+31 (0) 611060215

Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com Github: github.com/kamcpp

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kamcpp December 14, 2018 Page 2

• Sahab Pardaz Co.

Iran, Tehran

July 2016 - February 2017 (8 months)

Deep Learning Research Developer, Enterprise Software Architect, Project Manager

• Adro Co.

Iran, Tehran

June 2016 - February 2017 (9 months)

Senior Software Architect, Senior C++ Engineer

• Noavaran Tejarat Gostar Naeem Co.

Iran, Tehran

April 2015 - October 2016 (1 year, 6 months)

Chief Technical Officer, Senior Software Architect, Senior C/C++ Developer

• Sahab Pardaz Co.

Iran, Tehran

February 2015 - June 2015 (4 months)

Distributed Systems Architect, Senior Java SE/EE Engineer, C++ Engineer

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Persian(Native), English(Fluent), French(Intermediate), Dutch(Intermediate)

EDUCATION

• 2017 - Present

The Open University

Bachelor of Science in Physics (Astronomy and Planetary Science)

• 2004 - 2008

University of Isfahan

Isfahan, Iran

Bachelor of Software Engineering

INTERESTS

 Physics and Astronomty: Consmology, Astronomy, Quantum Physics, Quantum Mechanics, Particle Physics, Special and General Relativity, Theory of Everything, Photonics.

- Mathematics: Linear and Abstract Algebra, Probability Theory, Information Theory
- Cryptography: Information Security, Network Security, Security Algorithms, Quantum Information Theory, Quantum Key Distribution, Quantum Cryptography
- Philosophy: Western Philosophy, Sociology, Economics, Politics and Humanities
- Telecommunications: Modulation, Multiplexing, Codes, Telecommunication circuits, Photonics and optical fibers, IEEE 802.3 Protocols, Information Theory, Coding Theory, Computer Networks, etc
- Music and Musicology: Classic, Extreme Metal, Alternative Metal, Progressive Metal, Alternative Rock, etc